# 大家好 現在看一下那個金銀花有沒有開
Hi everyone! We're gonna have a look at the honeysuckles, and see if they have blossomed.
# 就有前面 前面很多的哦
There are a lot, just in front of us.
# 這個就是 我們這邊叫
This is, here it's called,
# 酸葉子 就這樣子 它葉子有點酸酸的
sour leaf. So here it is. It's a little bit sour.
# 有點酸酸的 甘甜甘甜的 這個
It's a bit sour and savory sweet, I mean...
# 很好吃的哦
It's really tasty.
# 味道還可以
It tastes not too bad.
# 因為現在還沒長齊 它剛剛長的嫩芽
Cuz it's still growing, only the shoots have come out.
# 嫩芽出來有那麼長的話 直接
When the shoots become that long, I can,
# 把這裡摘 摘下來吃
pick, pick this part right away.
# 酸酸甜甜 很開胃
It's sweet and sour, really appetizing.
# 好多這個小花
Here are a lot of this kind of flowers.
# 這樣一束一束摘起來 很漂亮的哦
I'm picking them in bunches. It's really pretty, you know.
# 這個我但這邊也不知道叫甚麼
I've no ideas how it's called here.
# 那個牛很喜喜歡吃的 這個
It's the cattle's favourite food.
# 我們這邊叫做
Here it's called,
# 紅花草 (註︰那他究竟是知還是不知....)
"red flower grass".
# 哇 好香
Wa! It smells great!
# 你看這個金銀花
Have a look at the honeysuckles!
# 剛剛有點花蕾
There are some newly grown buds,
# 小花蕾
small buds.
# 還有開花 來早啦
We come too early. They've still not yet blossomed.
# 晚一點的話
If we come later...
# 晚一點的話又不知道有沒有啦
But I wonder if there's anything left if we come later.
# 到時候我經常來看一下
I gotta check more often then,
# 經常來看一下
check more often.
# 這些都是
These are all,
# 金銀花
honeysuckles.
# 這邊應該用牛 牛拱的 拱那麼長
I think it's taken down, taken down by cattle. It's such a long path.
# 那麼 那麼乾淨這邊 (註︰他究竟想說甚麼....)
Everything is cleared here.
# 肯定有
Yea, I'm sure.
# 你看 這個好多這個拿藤包啊
Look! Here are a lot of chocolate vines.
# 長得一卡一卡的 你看 都是
They're in batches. Look! They're everywhere.
# 這個是花 花謝了之後就長這個果實
This is a flower. When the flower withers, it becomes a, well, a fruit.
# 這個是小拿藤包
This is a small chocolate vine.
# 一個
One,
# 三個 六個 四個
three, six, four
# 你看 好多啊
Look! A lot!
# 這棵也是
And this one too
# 到時候有些可能就是
Later, I think, it's like,
# 營養不好的話就算己慢慢凋謝掉
the weaker ones might be falling off by themselves.
# 如果好的話它就會慢慢地長出那個果來 嘖
And the stronger ones will turn gradually into fruits, nice!
# 就等你們長大啦 走啦
We'll wait, until you grow up. Let's go!
# 這是上次我送給大姑家的小狗
They are the puppies that I gave to my aunt last time.
# 狗
Puppies!
# 這雞 我又沒檢你的雞蛋
This chicken... C'mon, I'm not picking your eggs.
# 叫得那麼大聲 小狗
You're yelping so loudly, oh, puppies!
# 那麼胖 好像大了一點哦
So chubby. It seems that they've grown a bit, right?
# 過來
Come here!
# 過來 過來
Come here, come here!
# 它不肯過來
She doesn't want to come.
# 小狗
Puppy!
# 它也不肯過來喲 我碰一下它就呱呱叫
He's not coming. He yelps with all his might whenever I touch him.
# 現在很激動
You're now really excited
# 是不是
aren't you?
# 是不是想不到我還來看你 是不是
You've never expected that I'll still come and see you, have you?
# 就那我近 我會經常來看你的
We are living so close. I'll come and see you often.
# 這個是公的哦 那個是母的
This one is a boy, and that one is a girl.
# 小狗
Puppies!
# 過來
Come here!
# 好激動啊 它們
They're really excited!
# 不要我啦
I'm abandoned.
# 小狗 很開心啊 在這裡
Puppies! Are you very happy living here?
# 轉來轉去的 那麼寬 就它們兩個人
Here are just you two, running here and there, in such a large space.
# 小狗
Puppies!
# 過來
Come here!
# 哎喲 捉都捉不到你
Ayo! I can't even catch you!
# 嗯 小狗 過來
Um! Puppy! Come here!
# 你看 這個小母狗
Look! This little girl!
# 不許 不許動
No! Don't move!
# 不許動 怎機那麼調皮
Don't move! Why are you so naughty?
# 你要我摸一下是不是 你又不要我
You want my petting, don't you? No, you don't want me.
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 不許動
Don't move!
# 知不知道
Got it?
# 它不動敢
She dares not move.
# 你看 這個是
Look! She is,
# 戴了一個白手套
wearing a pair of white gloves.
# 你過來
It's your turn!
# 那個狗 它不肯過來
That puppy, doesn't want to come.
# 你看 這個 摸都摸(不)[SIC]到它
Look! I can't, I can't even touch it.
# 像個裡很乾淨的 毛色都好多啦
It's a very clean place here and their coats look so much better.
# 而吃得又好
They have very good food too.
# 是啊 每天的剩飯剩菜都給它們吃
Yup! They have all the leftover every day.
# 吃得好飽啊
They're very well fed.
# 比我們那裡好多啦 我們那只吃到米糠拌飯
It's so much better than our place. They had only rice and bran at our place,
# 啥都沒得吃
and nothing else.
# 過來
Come here!
# 你還在呵呵呵呵呵呵呵呵呵 是笑吧
You're always like, ho ho ho ho ho ho ho ho. Are you laughing?
# 是不是
Are you?
# 是不是你在笑 是不是
Are you laughing? Are you?
# 是不是在 在這裡天天都吃好的喝好的 是不是
Do you, do you have good food and food drinks here every day? Do you?
# 是不是
Do you?
# 你家主人呢
Where's you master?
# 你家主人去哪裡啦
Where's your master now?
# 啊 你家主人去哪裡啦
Ah! Where's your master now?
# 去哪裡啦
Where is he?
# 哎喲 這裡
Ayo! Here,
# 這裡好像受傷啦
Here seems to be a wound.
# 是不是兩 你們兩打架啦
I bet two, you two must had a fight, right?
# 不可以打架哦
No fighting! Got it?
# 你又那麼兇 你看
You know how fierce you are? Look!
# 笨 碰都碰不到你
You, you don't even let me touch you.
# 太壞啦 它
What a bad boy!
# 抓都抓不住的 一抓它都呱呱叫的 這個
Don't even think of catching him. He would yelp with all his might on your hand, this boy.
# 過來
Come here!
# 你看
Look!
# 挨都不會挨我一下
He doesn't even lean on me.
# 老是跑
He just runs away.
# 很激動哦
They're so excited,
# 又像小黑哦
just like Blacky.
# 你看 我抓了它 它不敢掙扎啦
Look! She's now on my hand and she dares not struggle anymore.
# 掙扎我就打它 打它屁屁
I would spank, spank her if she dares to struggle.
# 是不是
Am I right?
# 這個很可愛哦 你看 它的耳朵
She's really cute. I mean, her ears,
# 輕微的 輕微的
are a bit, a bit,
# 這樣 彎過來啦
like, floppy.
# 小狗
Puppy!
# 小狗 哎呀 是不是有跳蚤
Puppy! Aya! Is it a flea?
# 沒有
No, it's not.
# 很乖喲 小狗
She's a good girl, puppy.
# 要不要
Do you,
# 一起
wanna,
# 跳個舞
dance with me?
# 它不幹
No, she doens't.
# 來 跳舞
C'mon! Let's dance!
# 它不肯
She doesn't like it.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 到時候我們來 經常來看下它們
We'll come here, come here to see them more often.
# 看的它們慢慢長大
We'll see them grow to adults.
# 回去啦
Let's go back.